<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<XTbML><ContentClassification><TableIdentity>867</TableIdentity><ProviderDomain>soa.org</ProviderDomain><ProviderName>John Kalnberg</ProviderName><TableReference>Robert C. Toussaint and Francis T. Driscoll, “Note on New Mortality Tables for use in Pension Plans”, Proceedings of the Conference of Consulting Actuaries Vol. 30 (1980-81) Table 12, p. 73-74.</TableReference><ContentType tc="78">Annuitant Mortality</ContentType><TableName>1979 Buck Mortality Table - Female</TableName><TableDescription>1979 George B. Buck Mortality Table – Female. Minimum Age: 10 Maximum Age: 110</TableDescription><Comments>Study Data: Data from large retirement plans for which George B. Buck Consulting Actuaries, Inc. serves as actuary. Plans considered for the study were those with at least 1,000 pensioners, and had a formal disability plan. Data from banks and governmental plans was excluded as the study was intended to reflect mortality experience of industrial clients. Experience covered calendar years 1973-77. The study of active members constituted 2,827,801 life-years while the pensioners’ study was based on exposure of 573,809 life years. Methodology:  Crude rates at fifth ages were plotted and then intermediate values obtained from interpolation. Active service rates were adjusted by 10% to allow for the fact that exposures at the beginning of the years included those who withdrew or retired during the year. The gap between active members and pensioners was bridged by linear interpolation from age 55 to 70 for men and from age 50 to 70 for women. Since there was little data above 100, rates for men were set equal to rates from the 1971 Group Annuity Table (See SOA Table Identity 818). For women, the rates at ages 100 and over were equal to the male 1971 Group Annuity Table adjusted by the ratio of male to female mortality rates at age 99. At low ages (13 to 30) a third degree graduation was used that paralleled the 1969-71 U.S. Life Table. The use of a population table was felt appropriate for, at young ages, the Buck tables are mainly used for beneficiaries and contingent annuitants. For men, the curve was graded at age 13 into the unadjusted rates underlying the male 1974 Buck Mortality Table (See SOA Table Identity 866) while for women ages 10 through 15 were set equal to the unadjusted rates underlying the female 1974 Buck Mortality Table (See SOA Table Identity 865). The adjusted rates were then projected four years by Projection Scale D (See SOA Table Identities 904 and 905) developed in conjunction with the 1971 Group Annuity Mortality Table (See SOA Table Identities 817 and 818). So as to be appropriate for valuation purposes, a margin of conservatism was added. Rates, with the margins, were then graduated with a Whittaker-Henderson Type A method. Data Transcription Errors: None. Data Certified: 04/2013</Comments><KeyWord>Aggregate</KeyWord><KeyWord>Annuitant mortality</KeyWord><KeyWord>United States of America</KeyWord></ContentClassification><Table><MetaData><ScalingFactor>0</ScalingFactor><DataType tc="2">Floating Point</DataType><Nation tc="1">United States of America</Nation><TableDescription>1979 George B. Buck Mortality Table – Female. Minimum Age: 10 Maximum Age: 110</TableDescription><AxisDef id="Age"><ScaleType tc="3">Age</ScaleType><AxisName>Age</AxisName><MinScaleValue>10</MinScaleValue><MaxScaleValue>110</MaxScaleValue><Increment>1</Increment></AxisDef></MetaData><Values><Axis><Y t="10">0.00017</Y><Y t="11">0.00017</Y><Y t="12">0.00018</Y><Y t="13">0.00019</Y><Y t="14">0.00020</Y><Y t="15">0.00021</Y><Y t="16">0.00022</Y><Y t="17">0.00023</Y><Y t="18">0.00024</Y><Y t="19">0.00025</Y><Y t="20">0.00026</Y><Y t="21">0.00027</Y><Y t="22">0.00028</Y><Y t="23">0.00029</Y><Y t="24">0.00030</Y><Y t="25">0.00030</Y><Y t="26">0.00031</Y><Y t="27">0.00033</Y><Y t="28">0.00034</Y><Y t="29">0.00037</Y><Y t="30">0.00040</Y><Y t="31">0.00043</Y><Y t="32">0.00047</Y><Y t="33">0.00052</Y><Y t="34">0.00058</Y><Y t="35">0.00065</Y><Y t="36">0.00071</Y><Y t="37">0.00079</Y><Y t="38">0.00086</Y><Y t="39">0.00094</Y><Y t="40">0.00101</Y><Y t="41">0.00108</Y><Y t="42">0.00116</Y><Y t="43">0.00123</Y><Y t="44">0.00131</Y><Y t="45">0.00139</Y><Y t="46">0.00148</Y><Y t="47">0.00159</Y><Y t="48">0.00172</Y><Y t="49">0.00187</Y><Y t="50">0.00204</Y><Y t="51">0.00224</Y><Y t="52">0.00246</Y><Y t="53">0.00273</Y><Y t="54">0.00302</Y><Y t="55">0.00335</Y><Y t="56">0.00373</Y><Y t="57">0.00415</Y><Y t="58">0.00461</Y><Y t="59">0.00514</Y><Y t="60">0.00572</Y><Y t="61">0.00637</Y><Y t="62">0.00710</Y><Y t="63">0.00792</Y><Y t="64">0.00885</Y><Y t="65">0.00989</Y><Y t="66">0.01107</Y><Y t="67">0.01239</Y><Y t="68">0.01387</Y><Y t="69">0.01553</Y><Y t="70">0.01738</Y><Y t="71">0.01942</Y><Y t="72">0.02168</Y><Y t="73">0.02416</Y><Y t="74">0.02687</Y><Y t="75">0.02981</Y><Y t="76">0.03301</Y><Y t="77">0.03649</Y><Y t="78">0.04028</Y><Y t="79">0.04443</Y><Y t="80">0.04897</Y><Y t="81">0.05394</Y><Y t="82">0.05935</Y><Y t="83">0.06523</Y><Y t="84">0.07157</Y><Y t="85">0.07839</Y><Y t="86">0.08573</Y><Y t="87">0.09364</Y><Y t="88">0.10222</Y><Y t="89">0.11156</Y><Y t="90">0.12178</Y><Y t="91">0.13297</Y><Y t="92">0.14519</Y><Y t="93">0.15846</Y><Y t="94">0.17280</Y><Y t="95">0.18825</Y><Y t="96">0.20485</Y><Y t="97">0.22266</Y><Y t="98">0.24182</Y><Y t="99">0.26258</Y><Y t="100">0.28528</Y><Y t="101">0.31047</Y><Y t="102">0.33870</Y><Y t="103">0.37048</Y><Y t="104">0.40614</Y><Y t="105">0.44576</Y><Y t="106">0.48904</Y><Y t="107">0.53530</Y><Y t="108">0.58354</Y><Y t="109">0.63265</Y><Y t="110">1.00000</Y></Axis></Values></Table></XTbML>