<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<XTbML><ContentClassification><TableIdentity>865</TableIdentity><ProviderDomain>soa.org</ProviderDomain><ProviderName>John Kalnberg</ProviderName><TableReference>Robert C. Toussaint and Francis T. Driscoll, “Note on New Mortality Tables for use in Pension Plans”, Proceedings of the Conference of Consulting Actuaries Vol. 24 (1974-75) Table 6, p. 328-329.</TableReference><ContentType tc="78">Annuitant Mortality</ContentType><TableName>1974 Buck Mortality Table - Female</TableName><TableDescription>1974 George B. Buck Mortality Table – Female. Minimum Age: 10 Maximum Age: 110</TableDescription><Comments>Study Data: Data from large retirement plans for which George B. Buck Consulting Actuaries, Inc. serves as actuary. Plans considered for the study were those with at least 1,000 pensioners, and had a formal disability plan. For the most part, data from banks and governmental plans was excluded as the study was intended to reflect mortality experience of industrial clients. In order to provide adequate data on women prior to age 65, experience of female active members of a large state retirement system covering primarily clerical and administrative personnel was included. Experience covered calendar years 1969-72. The study of active members constituted 2,513,005 life-years while the pensioners’ study was based on exposure of 557,163 life years. Methodology:  Crude rates at fifth ages were plotted and then intermediate values obtained from interpolation. Active service rates were adjusted by 10% to allow for the fact that exposures at the beginning of the years included those who withdrew or retired during the year. The gap between active members and pensioners was bridged by linear interpolation from age 55 to 70 for men and from age 50 to 70 for women. Since there was little data above 90, rates for men and women were set equal to rates from the corresponding 1951 Group Annuity Tables (See SOA Table Identities 809 and 890). Additional adjustments were made to the data to account for irregularities. From age 20 to 12, crude rates graded into corresponding 1963 Buck Mortality Tables (See SOA Table Identities 863 and 864). The adjusted rates were then projected three years by Projection Scale D (See SOA Table Identities 904 and 905) developed in conjunction with the 1971 Group Annuity Mortality Table (See SOA Table Identities 817 and 818). So as to be appropriate for valuation purposes, a margin of conservatism was added. Rates, with the margins, were then graduated with a Whittaker-Henderson Type A method. Unlike the 1963 Buck Tables, these tables were not forced into a Makeham or Gompertz curve to permit application of the rule of uniform seniority to facilitate the calculation of joint life values. Advances in computer programs have made it possible to directly use basic mortality rates for such calculation. Data Transcription Errors: None. Data Certified: 04/2013</Comments><KeyWord>Aggregate</KeyWord><KeyWord>Annuitant mortality</KeyWord><KeyWord>United States of America</KeyWord></ContentClassification><Table><MetaData><ScalingFactor>0</ScalingFactor><DataType tc="2">Floating Point</DataType><Nation tc="1">United States of America</Nation><TableDescription>1974 George B. Buck Mortality Table – Female. Minimum Age: 10 Maximum Age: 110</TableDescription><AxisDef id="Age"><ScaleType tc="3">Age</ScaleType><AxisName>Age</AxisName><MinScaleValue>10</MinScaleValue><MaxScaleValue>110</MaxScaleValue><Increment>1</Increment></AxisDef></MetaData><Values><Axis><Y t="10">0.00018</Y><Y t="11">0.00018</Y><Y t="12">0.00018</Y><Y t="13">0.00019</Y><Y t="14">0.00020</Y><Y t="15">0.00021</Y><Y t="16">0.00022</Y><Y t="17">0.00024</Y><Y t="18">0.00025</Y><Y t="19">0.00027</Y><Y t="20">0.00028</Y><Y t="21">0.00028</Y><Y t="22">0.00030</Y><Y t="23">0.00032</Y><Y t="24">0.00034</Y><Y t="25">0.00036</Y><Y t="26">0.00038</Y><Y t="27">0.00040</Y><Y t="28">0.00043</Y><Y t="29">0.00047</Y><Y t="30">0.00050</Y><Y t="31">0.00055</Y><Y t="32">0.00060</Y><Y t="33">0.00065</Y><Y t="34">0.00072</Y><Y t="35">0.00079</Y><Y t="36">0.00087</Y><Y t="37">0.00096</Y><Y t="38">0.00105</Y><Y t="39">0.00115</Y><Y t="40">0.00126</Y><Y t="41">0.00138</Y><Y t="42">0.00151</Y><Y t="43">0.00164</Y><Y t="44">0.00178</Y><Y t="45">0.00194</Y><Y t="46">0.00210</Y><Y t="47">0.00228</Y><Y t="48">0.00248</Y><Y t="49">0.00269</Y><Y t="50">0.00292</Y><Y t="51">0.00318</Y><Y t="52">0.00346</Y><Y t="53">0.00376</Y><Y t="54">0.00410</Y><Y t="55">0.00447</Y><Y t="56">0.00487</Y><Y t="57">0.00531</Y><Y t="58">0.00579</Y><Y t="59">0.00632</Y><Y t="60">0.00690</Y><Y t="61">0.00755</Y><Y t="62">0.00827</Y><Y t="63">0.00908</Y><Y t="64">0.00999</Y><Y t="65">0.01100</Y><Y t="66">0.01215</Y><Y t="67">0.01344</Y><Y t="68">0.01489</Y><Y t="69">0.01653</Y><Y t="70">0.01836</Y><Y t="71">0.02041</Y><Y t="72">0.02270</Y><Y t="73">0.02525</Y><Y t="74">0.02808</Y><Y t="75">0.03121</Y><Y t="76">0.03469</Y><Y t="77">0.03853</Y><Y t="78">0.04279</Y><Y t="79">0.04751</Y><Y t="80">0.05273</Y><Y t="81">0.05850</Y><Y t="82">0.06485</Y><Y t="83">0.07181</Y><Y t="84">0.07939</Y><Y t="85">0.08762</Y><Y t="86">0.09650</Y><Y t="87">0.10606</Y><Y t="88">0.11633</Y><Y t="89">0.12736</Y><Y t="90">0.13920</Y><Y t="91">0.15196</Y><Y t="92">0.16575</Y><Y t="93">0.18074</Y><Y t="94">0.19715</Y><Y t="95">0.21520</Y><Y t="96">0.23514</Y><Y t="97">0.25723</Y><Y t="98">0.28171</Y><Y t="99">0.30885</Y><Y t="100">0.33884</Y><Y t="101">0.37186</Y><Y t="102">0.40799</Y><Y t="103">0.44723</Y><Y t="104">0.48946</Y><Y t="105">0.53440</Y><Y t="106">0.58163</Y><Y t="107">0.63058</Y><Y t="108">0.68061</Y><Y t="109">0.73108</Y><Y t="110">0.99999</Y></Axis></Values></Table></XTbML>